MARTIN INGRAM

email: martin.ingram@gmail.com



Summary: I am an expert in Bayesian statistical modelling and recently submitted my PhD on this topic. Before my PhD, I worked as a machine learning engineer in industry, where I developed deep learning models. I am passionate about combining solid code with solid mathematical modelling, and am keen to apply my skills to practical problems.

EDUCATION

University of Melbourne, Melbourne, Australia

2018-2021

PhD, Science (submitted October 2021)

Thesis title: Approximate Bayesian inference for large-scale hierarchical modelling

Expertise: Linear algebra, probability, Gaussian processes, programming with GPUs, variational inference

Imperial College London, London, United Kingdom

2014-2015

MSc., Computing Science, Grade: Distinction (82.8%)

Won "MSc. Group Project Prize" for best group project of the year

Courses (selection): Databases, Algorithms, Software Engineering, Program Design and Logic, C++

University of Cambridge, Cambridge, United Kingdom

2011-2014

BA., Natural Sciences (Physical). Grade: II.1

Peutinger-Gymnasium Augsburg, Augsburg, Germany

2001-2010

Abitur, Grade: 1.0

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Silverpond Pty Ltd

2016-2019

Machine Learning Engineer

Melbourne, Australia

- Consulting: Developed and evaluated deep learning models for clients
- Focus: Object detection and segmentation of aerial footage
- Developed company-internal software for object detection (Full time: 2016-2018; part time: 2018-2019)

Stratagem Technologies Limited

2015-2016

Quantitative Researcher

London, United Kingdom

• Developed a deep learning model to detect objects in soccer matches which outperformed previous approaches

SPI Lasers PLC

Summers, 2011-2013

Research Intern

Southampton, United Kingdom

• Developed software using MATLAB, Visual Basic and C# to aid research on fibre lasers

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming languages

Python, R, Bash

Software packages

PyMC3 (contributor), Stan, JAX, Tensorflow, pandas, numpy

Languages English (native speaker), German (native speaker)

ONLINE PROFILES

Website and blog

https://martiningram.github.io/

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/martin-ingram-48302782/

Google Scholar

https://scholar.google.com/citations?user=AZ-A7AEAAAAJ&hl=en